HTML5 Resume: Jared Pearce 2/20/17, 11:17 AM

Vamshi K Muthyala

FRONT-END DEVELOPER/BACK-END DEVELOPER

Developer enthusiastic about delivering a holistic, scalable approach to web development that not only meets industry best practices but also provides rich, engaging experiences for the end user. Expert strategist prepared for content interpretation, process integration, and software implementation that conforms to customer requirements and specifications. Contemporary artisan determined to decrease markup, incorporate consistent structure and produce elegant quality code for long-term product stability.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Application Developer

2015 - 2016

Capstone project - University California, U.S.A

- Created multiple Pages to increase the interaction between Student and faculty
- Analyzed requirements to develop ASP and Visual Basic applications to create more efficient processes for the organization
- Expertise in using HTML,CSS(Front-End) and Java,PHP(Back-End)
- Used Apache HTTP Web Server, SQL, created UML Diagrams.
- Evaluate and provide architectural solutions and lead the development efforts based on the Project requirements.
- Directly involved in the development efforts to produce custom data driven multi-tiered applications and Web Services.

Front End Developer

2013 - 2014

Connect Globe Solutions Hyderabad, India

- Reduced software development delays and increased code quality by adapting the peer-topeer code review process to leverage existing version control system functionality.
- Participated and succeeded in all stages of design, development, and deployment of new Java-Based vendor application system for financial-services industry.
- Provided energetic and meticulous feedback when evaluating visual design mocks and usability wireframes for feasibility of responsive HTML5/CSS3 conversion.
- Contributed to the in-house front end community by demonstrating how standard practices for CSS commenting and CSS rule-set structure generates high quality reusable code.
- Worked with Quality Engineering to deliver true to specification web experiences that resolved cross browser discrepancies and compatibility issues.

TechnoForte Benguluru, India

Established, in the final design specifications, visual layouts that conformed to a graphical user interface (GUI) framework, instituted strong typography and implemented appropriate color theory.

- Scoped, designed and deployed standardized learning templates programmed in HTML, CSS and JavaScript for consistent delivery of web-based training.
- Served integral role in 7-member team working for financial-services company.
- Presented high fidelity prototypes using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to engage customers in interactive feedback sessions, promote rapid design exploration and identify user patterns.
- Partnered in negotiating cost, schedule, and performance expectations with project leads and customers.
- Provided technical support for colleagues and clients; resolving 31 formal customer support tickets in the past year.

Assisted in defining and promoting technical avenues of growth, direction, vision and planning for the E-Learning Services Team.

- Promoted a clean, holistic, and scalable approach to the team's template architecture by using the Adobe Creative Suite.
- Developed, tested and implemented financial-services application to bring multiple clients into standard database format.

Researched and implemented clean coding practices and industry-touted methodologies within software development processes to ensure software quality, stability and graceful degradation.

- Used the Firefox Web Developer extension to iterate rapidly through the software development life cycle and to ensure pixel-perfect design implementation.
- Hand coded design specifications for accurate display in Firefox modifying, as needed, for other browsers.

Dotnet Developer

2011 - 2012

COIGN Hyderabad, India

- Designed and Developed various abstract classes, interfaces, classes to construct the business using c#.
- Used Data Contract as the standard mechanism in the WCF for serializing .NET object types into XML.
- Used Web Services (SOAP,WSDL) for Communicating with other application and component.
- Created SSRS Reports with SQL stored procedures and web services.

HTML5 Resume: Jared Pearce 2/20/17, 11:17 AM

 Implemented Data Access Layer using Entity Framework to connect, retrieve and update the data from SQL server.

• Extensive experience in web-based page and site designs using HTML,CSS,Themes,Master Pages, Site map, JavaScript, jQuery and AJAX.

SUMMER INTERNSHIPS

Web application Developer

Summer 2015

Capstone Project NPU (Northwestern polytechnic university) Fremont, CA

DotNet Developer

Summer 2013

COIGN Hyderabad, India

DotNet Developer

Summer 2012

COIGN Hyderabad, India

SAMPLE WORK

- Web Page Designs
- Java Code Development
- SDLC
- Cascading Style Sheets
- Solution Finder
- Setup,Configure
- Dotnet Frameworks

SOFTWARE

- Adobe CS
- Java Code
- CSS
- Visual Studio
- HTML
- SQL
- Phyton
- JavaScript
- UNIX
- Microsoft CRM
- Data Structures

HTML5 Resume: Jared Pearce 2/20/17, 11:17 AM

FORMAL EDUCATION

NorthWestern Polytechnic University

5/2016

Masters in Computer Science Minor: SDLC Fremont, CA

JNT University - Hyderabad

5/2013

B.Tech, Computer Science Hyderabad, India

CERTIFICATIONS

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Web Designing
- Core Java
- J2EE with Advanced java
- UNIX administration
- Programmers Marathon
- DotNet Frameworks

Contact Vamshi K. Muthyala

Address: Morrisville, North Carolina

CELL: 909-485-6268

Email: muthyalav@mail.npu.edu